A Guide to the Accomack County (Va.) Deed, Order and Will Books, 1632-1757
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Accomack County (Va.) Deed, Order and Will Books, 1632-1757
The Library of Virginia
Barcode numbers 1146285-1146290 and 1146292-1146296/Accomack County (Va.) Reels 1-11, 51-52 and 78-79
11 v. (3423 p.); 12 microfilm reels (8152 images)
Accomack County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a shipment of court papers from Accomack County.
Historical Information
Accomack County was formed in 1663 from Northampton County. Previous names: Accawmack, Accomac (original shire), Northampton (1643).
Scope and Content
Deed Books, 1632-1757, of Accomack County Court. The deed book records the name of the grantor and grantee, the residence of both individuals and the description of property being sold or transferred. The volumes have indexes except (1632-1640) which contains the first and last names of both parties. It is arranged alphabetically from A-Z.
Order Books, 1632-1697, of Accomack County Court. The order book records all matters brought before the court when it was in session. It provides a synopsis of cases in a neater, more organized form. These volumes are sometimes internally indexed; more rarely, there is a comprehensive index. A wide variety of information is found in this order book including: deeds, chancery causes, judgments, records of legal disputes heard before the county court and road orders. All the order books have indexes except (1632-1640).
Will Books, 1632-1729, of Accomack County Court. The will book includes the name of testator, list of heirs and year the wills were proven in court and probate records such as inventories and appraisements. All the will books have indexes except (1632-1640).
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Accomack Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult A Guide to Virginia County and City Records On Microfilm found on the Library of Virginia web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Accomack County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Geographical Names:
Accomack County (Va.) -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Deeds -- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Judicial records-- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Land records -- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Order books -- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Will books -- Virginia -- Accomack County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Accomack County.
Contents List
- Orders, Wills and Deeds #1 1632-1640 (Barcode 1146292)
- Deeds and Wills 1663-1666 (Barcode 1146285)
- Deeds and Wills 1664-1671 (Barcode 1146286)
- Orders and Wills and C 1671-1673 (Barcode 1146293)
- Wills and Deeds 1676-1690 (Barcode 1146295)
- Wills, Deeds and Orders 1678-1682 (Barcode 1146294)
- Wills and C Orders 1692(82)-1697 (Barcode 1146296)
- Deeds Wills and C Part 2 1715-1729 (Barcode 1146288)
- Deeds, Wills and C 1715-1729 (Barcode 1146287)
- Deeds 1746-1757 (Barcode 1146290)
- Deeds 1746-1757 (Barcode 1146289)